Elsie Clews Parsons Papers 1835-1944 Mss.Ms.Coll.29
American Philosophical Society
- Elsie Clews Parsons Papers I, 572 P25.1
  - Series I. Correspondence (1-4), 1921-1941; 1.5 linear feet
    - Gorrell, Juan, 1940-1941; 3 items (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, April 17, 1941; 23; 1p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, April 22, 1941; 24; 2p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
      - TLS to Juan L. Gorrell, April 26, 1941; 25; 2p.; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, May 5, 1941; 26; 1p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, June 8, [1941]; 27; 1p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
      - TLS to Juan L. Gorrell, reply to June 8 no. 27 (incomplete), 28; 1p.; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, Aug. 11, 1941; 29; 1p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, Oct. 11 [1941]; 30; 1p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, Oct. 13, [1941]; 31; 2p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
      - TLS to Elsie Clews Parsons, Oct. 25, 1941; 32; 1p.; Gorrell, Juan L. (Box 2)
    - Goubauld, Antonio, 1941; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3108
    - Gregory, Alyse (Box 2)
    - Guthe, Carl E. (Box 2)
    - H., Francis (Box 2)
    - Hallowell, A. Irving (Box 2)
    - Hand, Learned (Box 2)
    - Hanson, Avery T. (Box 2)
    - Hare, David. Note on Hare's portfolio and letter from Betty, 1941; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3078
    - Hartman, Howard R. (Box 2)
    - Hatch, Charles B. (Box 2)
    - Haury, Dr., 1937; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3068
    - Heard, Alexander, 1941; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3109
    - Heflin, Woodford (Box 2)
    - Herskovits, Melville J., 1941; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3682, 3683
    - Herskovits, Melville J. (Box 2)
    - Herzog, George, 1937; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 2957
    - Herzog, George (Box 2)
    - Hill, W. W., ca.1940; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3082
    - Hodge, F. W., 1937; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3064
    - Hoebel, E. Adamson (Box 2)
    - Hoijer, harry, 1940; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 2388
    - Holt, Hamilton (Box 2)
    - Howland,Alice G. (Box 2)
    - Hunkins, R. V. (Box 2)
    - Hutton, A. G. (Box 2)
    - Identification (Box 2)
    - Jaegerhuber, Werner A. (Box 2)
    - Jijon y Caamano, Jacinto, 1940; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3111
    - Johnson, Owen (Box 2)
    - Jones, Volney H., 1938; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 1556
    - Kelly, Isabel, 1938; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 436
    - Kennard, Edward A., 1938-1939; 3 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 1557
    - Kennard, Edward A. (Box 2)
    - Kennedy, John D. (Box 2)
    - Kennedy, Lissa Parsons (Box 2)
    - Kent, R. G. (Box 2)
    - Keur, Dorothy L. (Box 2)
    - Kidder, Alfred V., 1923-1938; 3 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 2384, 3222
    - King, Dale S. (Box 2)
    - Kluckhohn, Clyde (Box 2)
    - Knobhauer, Mary (Box 2)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., Inc. (Box 2)
    - Kroeber, A. L. (Box 2)
    - L, Mabel (Box 2)
    - LaBarre, Weston, 1937; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3711
    - LaFarge, Oliver, 1929; 3 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 574
    - Lambert, E. V. (Box 2)
    - Lange, Charles, 1941; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3987
    - Law, George (Box 2)
    - Lawry, George A. (Box 2)
    - Lee, Dorothea D. (Box 2)
    - Leland, Waldo G. (Box 2)
    - Lesser, Alexander (Box 2)
    - Lestrade, G. P. (Box 2)
    - Lewis, Margaret, 1937; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3988
    - Lieurance, Thurlow (Box 2)
    - Light, G., 1938; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 575
    - Liming, George W. (Box 2)
    - Lincoln, J. Steward, 1936; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 714
    - Linton, Ralph (Box 2)
    - Lowie, Robert H., 1936-1941; 10 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 576, 1863, 3076, 3172, 3795
    - Lowie, Robert H. (Box 2)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1939-1941; 7 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3712
    - McDuffey, Joseph (Box 2)
    - McKern, W. C. (Box 2)
    - Martin, Paul S., 1938-1939; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3065, 3066
    - Martin, Paul S. (Box 2)
    - Mason, John Alden (Box 2)
    - Mayer, Mrs. M., 1940; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 1558
    - Mead, Margaret, 1939; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3934
    - Means, Philip Ainsworth, 1941; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3131
    - Medical Clarion (Box 2)
    - Mekeel, H. Scudder, 1938-1939; 8 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3077
    - Mekeel, H. Scudder (Box 2)
    - Mera, H. P., 1941; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3067
    - Merrill, E. (Box 2)
    - Mills, Ogden L. (Box 2)
    - Mirabel, Antonio, 1939; 2 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 3713
    - Mishkin, Bernard, 1939; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 578
    - Miscellany (Box 2)
    - Mitla, Town of Souls (Box 2)
    - Morgan, Mrs. Anita (Box 2)
    - Nancy Couture, Inc. (Box 2)
    - Natural History Magazine (Box 2)
    - New Mexico Association on Indian Affairs (Box 2)
    - New School for Social Research, Inc. (Box 2)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 2)
    - North Haven, Maine (Box 2)
    - Oakman, Elise (Box 2)
    - Opler,Marvin K., 1938-1941; 12 items (Box 2)
      Freeman 400, 3829
    - Opler,Marvin K. (Box 2)
    - Osanai, Iva T., 1939; 1 item (Box 2)
      Freeman 3079
    - Osgood, Cornelius (Box 2)
    - Paramount Pictures (Box 3)
    - Memorandum on relations with Spanish America, 1940; 1 item; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 3)
      Freeman 3688
    - Letters in re. Mitla, Town of the Souls, 1936; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 3)
      Freeman 3933
    - Pawnee kinship terms, n.d.; 1 item; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 3)
      Freeman 2666
    - Project report for Navajo archaeology, 1939; 1 item; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 3)
      Freeman 2381
    - Parsons, Elsie Clews (Box 3)
    - Parsons, Herbert (Box 3)
    - Parsons, John E. (Box 3)
    - Parsons, Mary (Box 3)
    - Patterson, Rufus Lenoir (Box 3)
    - Peters, Robeson (Box 3)
    - Powell, Thomas Reed (Box 3)
    - Profitt, Charles G. (Box 3)
    - Quisumbing, Eduardo (Box 3)
    - Rael, Juan B. (Box 3)
    - Railway Express Agency (Box 3)
    - Ray (Box 3)
    - Redfield, Robert, 1937-1941; 29 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 579, 748, 3119, 3919, 3940
    - Redfield, Robert (Box 3)
    - Reichard, Gladys, 1939-1941; 7 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 2386
    - Reichard, Gladys (Box 3)
    - Reiter, Paul, 1939; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 3069
    - Robinson, Randolph (Box 3)
    - Roosevelt, Sara Delano, Tribute Committee (Box 3)
    - Rosenberger, E. G. (Box 3)
    - Rosett, Joshua (Box 3)
    - Rydal,Press (Box 3)
    - St. Paul's School (Box 3)
    - Santa Fe (N.M.) First National Bank (Box 3)
    - Sapir, Edward (Box 3)
    - Schloss (Box 3)
    - Scholarly Monthly (Box 3)
    - Scott, Donald (Box 3)
    - Sedgwick, Sher (Box 3)
    - Seligman, C. G. (Box 3)
    - Setzler, Frank M. (Box 3)
    - Simkhovitch, Mary (Box 3)
    - Simmons, Leo W., 1941; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 1562
    - Smith, Marian K. (Box 3)
    - South American Handbook (Box 3)
    - South American Trip - Miscellany (Box 3)
    - Spier, Leslie, 1937-1941; 19 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 3927
    - Spier, Leslie (Box 3)
    - Stagg, F. L. (Box 3)
    - Stammer, P. (Box 3)
    - Stearns, Harold E. (Box 3)
    - Stechert, G. E., & Co. (Box 3)
    - Stern, Bernhard J (Box 3)
    - Stevenson, J. H., & Company (Box 3)
    - Steward, Julian, 1939-1940; 6 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 3120, 3687, 3690
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps (Box 3)
    - Stout, D. B. (Box 3)
    - Strong, W. Duncan, 1939; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 2382
    - Strong, W. Duncan (Box 3)
    - Sturges, Mia P. (Box 3)
    - Swanton, John R., 1921, 1940; 3 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 480a, 2668
    - T., B. R. (Box 3)
    - Taylor, Archer (Box 3)
    - Tello, Julio (Box 3)
    - Thompson, Stith (Box 3)
    - Thorburn, Lois, 1941; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 3121
    - Thorburn, Lois (Box 3)
    - Thurber, Mrs. Francis B. [Louise] (Box 3)
    - Titiev, Mischa, 1938-1940; 5 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 1565
    - Titiev, Mischa (Box 3)
    - Toro, Angélica Q. de (Box 3)
    - Torrey, J. Howard (Box 3)
    - Toskvig, Signe (Box 3)
    - Trager, George L., 1938-1941; 6 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 750, 3155, 3156, 3725
    - True, Clara D., 1939; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 3722
    - True, Clara D. (Box 3)
    - Tweedy, Elizabeth R. (Box 3)
    - Underhill, Ruth, 1939-1939; 6 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 2645
    - U.S. Department of the Interior (Box 3)
    - U.S. Treasury Department (Box 3)
    - University of Chicago Press (Box 3)
    - University of Edinburgh. Library (Box 3)
    - Unknown (Box 3)
    - Vaillant, George C. (Box 3)
    - Valkenburgh, Richard Van (Box 3)
    - Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 3)
    - Voegelin, Erminie W (Box 3)
    - Wagley, Charles, 1937; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 2103
    - Wagley, Charles (Box 3)
    - Wallis, Wilson D., 1939; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 2234
    - Watkins, Dr., 1939; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 1560
    - Waters, Frank (Box 3)
    - Weitzner, Bella (Box 3)
    - Wenicks, Elna (Box 3)
    - White, Leslie A. (Box 3)
    - Whitefield, Bernard (Box 3)
    - Whitman, William, 1938; 2 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 2605
    - Whorf, Benjamin L., 1937; 1 item (Box 3)
      Freeman 3089
    - Willey, Gordon R. (Box 3)
    - Wissler, Clark (Box 3)
    - Woodbury, Richard B., 1941; 3 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 1551
    - Woodward, B. D. (Box 3)
    - Yuan, T. L. (Box 3)
    - Zingg, Robert M., 1934-1935; 2 items (Box 3)
      Freeman 1598, 1600
  - Series II. Notes, manuscripts, etc. (5-67)
    - Correspondence with Isleta, New Mexico, 1936-1941; 5; ALsS and TLsS, 338 leaves (Box 3)
    - Picuris., 1925; 6; 1 notebook, 7-3/4x5 and map, 17x37. (Box 3)
    - Pecos - Tewa - Taos, 7; 1 notebook, 5x3-1/4. (Box 3)
    - Taos, 8; 1 notebook and 22 leaves, 9x5-3/4 and 11-1/2x8. (Box 3)
    - Taos, 1937.; 9; 1 notebook, 9x5-3/4 (Box 3)
    - Isleta tales, 1925-1927; 10; 8 notebooks, 9x4-3/4 and 8x5. (Box 3)
    - Taos Notebooks, 1922-1930; 11; 11 notebooks, 8x5; 9x5; and 7x5. (Box 3)
    - Antilles material. Haiti; D., 1927.; 12; 5 notebooks, 8-3/4x4-3/4. (Box 3)
    - Antilles material (Cariacos, St. Vincent, St. Lucia, St. Croix, St. Kitts, Antigua), 1925; 13; 4 notebooks, 8x5 and 9x4-3/4. (Box 3)
    - Antilles material (Trinidad, all four, and Grenada - part of IV), 14; 4 notebooks, 8x5. (Box 3)
    - Antilles material (Martinique, all five, and St. Lucia, part of one), 15; 5 notebooks, 8x5. (Box 3)
    - Antilles material (Guadaloupe, Puerto Rico), 16; 6 notebooks in 7 volumes, 9x5 (Box 3)
    - Antilles material. St. Dominica (2); Antigua, St. Kitts, St. Croix and St. Thomas (part of 1); and New Mexico material (part of 1)., 17; 3 notebooks, 8x5. (Box 3)
    - Hopi materials, 1885-1892; 18; 4 notebooks, 6-1/2x4; 7-1/2x4; 8x4-3/4 and 9-3/4x6-1/4. (Box 3)
      - Hopi Indian ceremonial objects, 1885-1892
      - Hopi Indian pottery for kiva ceremony, 1885-1892
      - Hopi Indian antiquities, 1885-1892
      - Navajo Indian masks, 1885-1892
    - Mitla journals (one marked Zapoteca), 19; 5 notebooks, 6-1/2x5 (Box 3)
    - Mayo - Yaqui; 1 notebook, 9x5-3/4., 1932; 20 (Box 3)
    - Jamaica Negro proverbs, sayings, etc., Dec. 8, 1892; 22; 1 notebook, 9x7.; Drinkwater, George R. (Box 3)
    - Recuerdos tiernos amorosos en el nacimiento del Verbo dierno dios y salvador del mundo, 1835-1896; 23; 148 items, most 8-3/4x6-1/2; Pastorella(s?) (Box 3)
      In Spanish. Religious writings
    - Isleta pictures and manuscripts, 24; 10 items, various sizes (Box 3)
      For additional Isleta correspondence, see No.5
      See Extra-oversized material. The bulk of these items are at the Smithsonian Institution.
    - Bibliography, 25; TMs, 31p. (74p.of copies) 11x8-1/2 and 8-1/2x5-1/2.; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Zuni and Isleta Indians 8 items, 1938; 26; Adair, John (Box 3)
    - Photographs of Indians and Taos, 27; 48 items (Box 3)
      Includes some negatives
      - Taos dwellings, 1925
    - Mitla songs and photographs (Oaxaca region), 1930; 28; 301 items (Box 3)
      Includes 14 songs, 183 photos, ca.100 negatives of Oaxaca; 3 drawings and an article on Zapotec words; letter from E. D. Merrill to Franz Boas, May 13, 1930.
    - Photographs of ZuC1i, 29; 8 photos, 54 negs. (Box 3)
    - Dominica Notebooks, 21; 3 notebooks, 8x6-1/2. (Box 3)
    - Plates from Bureau of American Ethnology and 2 pictures drawn by Albert Looking Elk, 30; 2 ms.and 126 plates. 11x7-1/2; 10x6-1/2 and 10-3/4x8. (Box 3)
    - Cachina tables: Pueblo Indian religion, 31; ca.150 items (Box 3)
      Misc.notes and correspondence with R.H.Lowie, A.V.Kidder, etc., some in fragmentary condition.
    - Tewa and Jemez pictures, printed and original, 32; 20 items (Box 3)
      Includes 10 printed pictures; 4 original; 5 ms. sheets in pencil, and reprint from the American Anthropologist 20 (1918): E.C.Parsons. "War God Shrines of Laguna and ZuC1i".
    - Caddo material, 33; 20 items (Box 3)
      Includes correspondence with Erminie W. Voegelin; and 2 printed items by Erminie Wheeler Voegelin.
    - The World Changes, 34; ca.1,000 p. (Box 3)
      Unpublished manuscript; some newspaper clippings.
    - Trip to Greece, 35; 1 notebook and 16 typed leaves. 11x8-1/2 and 7x4-1/2 (Box 3)
    - Note on sleep, 36; 3 cys, 2 letters (Box 3)
      Rejection letters from AAAS and Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology. Also: reprint: Walter Freeman and James W. Watts, "An interpretation of the functions of the frontal lobe" Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine
    - Notes on parallels between Cora-Huichol and the Pueblos, 1934-1935; 37; 29p. (total) (Box 3)
      Incldues correspondence with Robert M. Zingg.
    - Potsherds from 2 different pots., 38 (Box 3)
    - Riddles, folk tales and poems (York Village, Maine), 39; 1p.of ms.and 8p.typed. 2p.cc. 11x8-1/2. (Box 3)
    - Filipino village reminiscence, 1939; 40; 1 notebook, loose sheets.; Parsons, Elsie Worthington Clews, 1875-1941 (Box 3)
      Galley proof of Scientific Monthly article, 1939. Printed items, of 6 strips. 23x7-1/4. Also TMs outline of article, 37 leaves. 26 leaves, and 1 notebook. 2p.listing of kinship terms in the Philippines by Philip Olivares.
    - Birth control material, 1926-1938; 41 (Box 3)
      3 pamphlets by W.F. Ogburn, 2 newspaper clippings, letter from W.F.Ogburn; Oct. 11, 1937; and article, published in Stearns: America Now, by Parsons, in typescript of 6p; with correspondence concerning the publication. Typed D. 8p. 11x8-1/2 and 8x5. (Title of article: The Family.)
    - Natural History, vol. 17, Sept. 1938; 42 (Box 3)
      - American Antiquity vol.VI, no.3. Steward, Julian H. Petroglyphs of California and Adjoining States. U.of Cal.Press. Berkeley, Cal., Jan. 1941, 1929. (Box 3)
      - Navaho Notebook, 1885-1891; 1 vol. (3p. of typed notes); Stephen (Box 3)
        Probably published. Origin myths, illustrations from notebooks.
    - Indian trait survey. D. 34p. 8-1/2 xll. Correspondence in re Indian trait survey; Typed L. 17p. 11x8-1/2. E.W.Gifford. Religious preparations for Hunt. Typed D. 54p. 11x8-1/2., 1937.; 43; Gifford, Edward W. (Box 3)
    - Tratado muy utile e bien fundado de las supersticiones y hechicerias, y varios conjuros y abusiones y otras cosas al caso tocantes, y de la posibilidad y remedio de ellas, 44; TMs, [1], 76p.; CastaC1ega, Martin de (Box 3)
    - Witchcraft material, 1938-1939; 6p. (Box 3)
    - Correspondence with Margaret Lewis, 1939; 45; 4p. (Box 3)
      - "ZuC1is offer five dances", 7 leaves, 1 note. (Box 3)
        Printed item of 2 leaves. Note on incest by Parsons.
      - Questions asked Isletan, TMs, 1p.; notes, 14 items (Box 3)
    - "A Pre-Spanish Record of Hopi Ceremonies" American Anthropologist, 1938, 1938-1940; 46 (Box 3)
      Correspondence in re Sikyatki bowl in The Southwest Museum.
    - Pueblo material, misc., 47; 113 leaves, 10 pr. items (Box 3)
      "Parts may have been used but no plan to incorporate these in any work under way"- A.Nagel.
    - Antilles material - Unpublished, 48 (Box 3)
      - La guia ou dammier, 60p. (Box 3)
      - [Brer Rabbit and the] Riding Horse. Nevis Island, 2 leaves (Box 3)
      - Martinique (Modock) Tales, which stories, true stories, songs, etc., 189p. (Box 3)
        In French and English.
      - Verses (Revised) originals. Montserrat, St. Eustasius verses not revised yet, 171p. (Box 3)
      - Lesser Antilles. Current beliefs, 125 leaves (Box 3)
      - Antilles. Current beliefs, 81p. (Box 3)
      - St. Croix Stories, 7p. AMs. and 17p. TMs (Box 3)
      - Dominica. Revised, 67 leaves (Box 3)
        In French.
      - Martinique material, 13 leaves (Box 3)
    - Antilles. Unpublished., 49 (Box 3)
      - Martinique original tales, 1; 380 leaves (Box 3)
      - Modock misc. Unrevised. (Marginique tales), 2; 60 leaves, 10p. cc., 3 leaves notes (Box 3)
      - Modock misc. Unrevised, 3; 47 leaves c.c. (Box 3)
      - Folk Tales and Riddles from the Lesser Antilles., 4; [3], 264, [266]p.; Fauset, A. H. (Box 3)
      - West Indian Glossary, 5; 116 leaves and 2 notepads (Box 3)
      - St. Lucia. Riddles, tales, etc., 6; 39 leaves (Box 3)
        In French. Also, printed: S. H.King, King's Book of Chanties.
      - [The Goat and the Dawg], 7; 2 leaves and c.c. (Box 3)
      - Samana Bay - Santo Domingo; Bahamas, 8; 1 notebook (Box 3)
        Also 38p. transcript and c.c.
      - West Indian material (Misc.), 9; 80p. (Box 3)
        Correspondence in re. publication on Martinique. Also list (47p) of words, in French, from Marginique.
      - West Indies. Misc. Folk tales, etc. (Martinique?), 10; 113 leaves, 2 newspaper clippins (Box 3)
        Some in French.
      - Guadaloupe. "La moitie d'un", 11; 8p. (Box 3)
      - Guadaloupe. School material (Trois Rivieres). Visiting cards of acquaintances, 12; 100 leaves, 6 cards (Box 3)
      - St. Croix, St. Thomas, 13; 27 leaves (Box 3)
    - Antilles., 50 (Box 3)
      - Martinique (Modock) Misc. tales: Guadaloupe True Story, 1; 207 leaves (Box 3)
      - Songs (Modock), original and duplicate, 2; 41p. AMs, 67p. TMs (and c.c.), 1 newspaper clipping (Box 3)
      - Martinique, Guadaloupe, Haiti, St. Lucia. Misc. proverbs sayings, songs, etc., 3; 163 leaves. (Box 3)
      - Modock. "True Stories" Original and duplicate, 4; 65p. and c.c. (Box 3)
      - West Indian. Current beliefs, 5; 93 leaves (Box 3)
      - West Indian. Verses revised, 6; 146p. (Box 3)
        In French
      - Old material from the Antilles, 7; 126p. (Box 3)
        Contains some correspondence.
    - Pueblo of Tewa. Photographs and negatives, "of little value", 1918-1926; 51; 218 prints, 54 negs. (Box 3)
      - Buffalo dance
      - Two Tewa women, child
      - Tewa adobe dwellings
      - Tewas at settlement
      - Adobe wall
      - Tewa man, adobe dwelling
      - Adobe dwellings, Tewa settlement
      - Adobe dwelling with ladder
    - No number, 52 (Box 3)
    - Current in 1939, 53; 62p., newspaper clipping (Box 3)
      Important misc. Remarks: "Better keep - G.A.R." In English and Spanish. Contents in part: Correspondence; J.de la Fuente, "Las ceremonias de la eluvia entre los Zapotecos de hoy"; William R. Bascom, "The relationship of Yoruba folklore to divining.
    - Correspondence of H. A.Douglas and E. C.Parsons in re. Taos dances, 1889, 1941; 54; 6p., 30 photos (Box 3)
      Photos of Taos pueblo.
    - No number, 55 (Box 3)
    - Notes of mummy cave from Stephen's notebooks, 56; 32p. (Box 3)
    - "Synopsis of non-material culture traits characterizing the Ladinos of Agua Escondida. Western Highlands, Guatemala", 57; 15p. (Box 3)
    - No number, 58 (Box 3)
    - No number, 59 (Box 3)
    - Notes on Peguchi and other South America Tribes., 60 (Box 3)
      - Ecuador, March 6.; 1 notebook (Box 3)
      - Peguchi, 1 notebook (Box 3)
      - Ecuador notes, 111p. (Box 3)
      - Peguchi. Worked over material. Karstin notes, mostly used. Southeastern South America parallels, 68p. (Box 3)
      - Photographs, Ecuador, 100 prints, 27 negs. (Box 3)
        - View of house-types, Peguche.
        - Musicians of San Rafael, Easter Monday.
        - Peguche (?) woman, working with wood., ca. 1940
        - Peguche (?) women, working with loom., ca. 1940
      - Notes. Ecuador, 1938; 45p.; 1 notebook, etc. (Box 3)
        Includes 4 newspaper clippings; 3 postal cards; 2 dried twigs of leaves; and 1 printed item: Juan Morales. Ecuador.
      - Misc. Ecuador material, 93p., 2 newspaper clippings, reprint (Box 3)
        Reprint: John Gillin. "The Quichua-Speaking Indians... Ecuador."
      - Misc. Peruvian material, 61p. (Box 3)
    - Pueblo Indian Religion., 61 (Box 3)
      - [Pueblo Indian Religion. Preface?], 43p. (Box 3)
      - Flute ceremony, 6p. (Box 3)
      - Hoinawe, 1p. (Box 3)
      - Snake ceremony, 3p. (Box 3)
      - Niman Kachina, 6p. (Box 3)
      - Girls' dances, 1p. (Box 3)
      - WaqC6l, 2p. (Box 3)
      - Lalakunte ceremony, 2p. (Box 3)
      - Buffalo dance, 3p. (Box 3)
      - Water Snake (PalC6kün) dance, 2p. (Box 3)
      - War God ceremony, 2p. (Box 3)
      - Soyala, 8p. (Box 3)
      - OC1kwati Kachina dances, 1p. (Box 3)
      - Moüngtoshap, 1p. (Box 3)
      - Salako Kachina, 2p. (Box 3)
      - Powamu, 10p. (Box 3)
      - On inviting Kachina from another village, 10p. (Box 3)
      - The Separation of functions of Curing and of Weather Control in ZuC1i and Keresan ceremonialism, 24 leaves (Box 3)
      - Interrelations of cults, 30p. (Box 3)
      - Memorandum on Koyenishi and Newakiva, 3p. (Box 3)
      - Kachina, 10p. (Box 3)
      - The Clan as a Ceremonial Organization, 20p. (Box 3)
      - Notes on Hopi ceremonies, 61p. (Box 3)
      - Hopi and ZuC1i ceremonialism, 1p. (Box 3)
      - Table A-C: Clans and ceremonial associations, 3p. (Box 3)
      - Change: Acculturation Growth and Decay, 19p. (Box 3)
      - Like cures Like, 2p. (Box 3)
      - Sickness: Witchcraft: Old Age: Death, 10p. (total) (Box 3)
      - Tribe [crossed off], 5p. (Box 3)
      - The Spirits: Cosmology. The Spirits. Rejected, 10p. (Box 3)
      - Reject[ed] from Preface, 4p. (Box 3)
      - Whipping of the Children, and Advent of the Water Snake, ZuC1i, 5p. (Box 3)
      - Laguna Emergence myth, 3p. (Box 3)
      - Cochiti Emergence myth, 5p. (Box 3)
      - [Ritual violations?], 15p. (Box 3)
      - Cultural processes observable in Puebo religion, 6p. (Box 3)
      - Summer solstice ceremonial, 1891; 1920; 8p., 1 notebook (Box 3)
      - Notes on traits, 3 leaves (Box 3)
      - NatC6C1a or initiation into wC6wC6chimtu, Singers, Horn and Agave Societies, Nov. 1891; 40p. (total) (Box 3)
      - The Institution of the Governship, 20p. (Box 3)
      - Plates used in Pueblo Indian religion, 5 leaves (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous notes, ca.150p. (Box 3)
    - Elsie Clews Parsons. Folk-Lore of the Antilles, 62; [29], 735, [1], 190; 12; 35p. (Box 3)
      American Folk Lore Society, vol.26, pt.3. Carbon copy. In French and English
    - Peguchi. Canton of Otavalo, Province of Imbabuka, Ecuador. A study of Andean Indians, 63; [3]345p; 59p. c.c. (Box 3)
      Published by the University of Chicago Press. Carbon copy in part.
      - Peguchi. Notes, etc (Box 3)
    - Acoma material., 64 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence with various personsTLsS, 1932-1941; 9p. (Box 3)
      - White, Leslie A. Autobiography of an Acoma Indian, 26p. (Box 3)
      - White, Leslie A. Supplementary data on Acoma, 83p. (Box 3)
      - White, Leslie A. Acoma tales, 59p. (Box 3)
      - Stirling, Matthew W. Acoma records Draft., 443 leaves (Box 3)
      - Stirling, Matthew W. Origin myth of Acoma and other records: Leslie A.White. Autobiography of an Acoma Indian: Supplementary data on Acoma; and Acoma Tales, [40], 172p. (Box 3)
        Also correspondence of 4p., 1941.